Guide to the Ralph Cipriano Italitan American collection, 1937-1975 MS2277
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Ralph Cipriano Italian American collection
1937-1975
1942-1968
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Cipriano, Ralph
MS2277
0.75 Linear Feet 1 document box 1 slim document box
This collection contains personal papers of Ralph Cipriano (1897-1975) related to his work with the Lido Civic Club and other Italian American organizations in Washington, DC from 1937-1975. Cipriano was a charter member and 1938 president of the Lido Club. Topics covered in the collection include the 1940s war bond drives, Italian American social events, charitable giving, and correspondence with prominent Washingtonians.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Madeline Sapienza, 2009 (Accession 2009.056)
Ralph Cipriano
Ralph Cipriano (1897-1975) served and led the Italian American community in Washington, DC for nearly 50 years.
Born Raffaele Cipriano on the island of Ischia, Italy, he immigrated to the US with his family as a youth. Cipriano attended high school in Providence, Rhode Island, and moved to Washington, DC shortly after graduation. He became an agent for the New York Life Insurance Company in 1926. During his career, he was recognized for his outstanding salesmanship by being named to the President's Council and the Million Dollar Round Table. Cipriano also contributed to Italian American cultural life in Washington, helping to found the Lido Civic Club in 1929 and remaining a lifelong member. He served as president in 1938, the same year he became totally blind, and led a highly successful war bond drive in 1942. The Treasury Department acknowledged his work by giving him its Silver Award. In 1968, Cipriano was awarded the title of "Commandatore dell' Ordine della Stella della Solidarieta Italiana," the highest honor an Italian-American can receive from the Italian government, for outstanding service in Italian-American relations.
Ralph Cipriano died in Washington, DC in 1975.
Arrangement
This collection is not fully processed and series have not been identified.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains correspondence, event programs, newsletters, photographs, and pamphlets. The material dates from 1937-1975. These are personal papers of Ralph Cipriano related to his association with the Lido Civic Club of Washington and other Italian American organizations. Cipriano was a charter member and 1938 president of the Lido Club. Topics covered in the collection include the 1940s war bond drives, Italian American social events, charitable giving, and correspondence with prominent Washingtonians, including Judge John J. Sirica, Senator John O. Pastore, the Very Reverend Edward B. Bunn, Ugo Carusi, and Italian Ambassadors.
Italian Americans -- Washington, D.C.; Italian Americans; Washington (D.C.) -- History; Lido Civic Club
- Carusi, Ugo - Portrait with Inscription, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Lido Civic Club - Monthly Newsletter "Chips", 1937-1942 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Carusi, Ugo - Speeches, 03/08/1942 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Cipriano, Ralph - Correspondence and Selective Service Registration Certificate, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Cipriano, Ralph - Correspondence on War Bond Drive and Columbus Day Celebration, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- War Bonds Sales - Third Drive by Italian American Victory Council, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Italian American Victory Council of Washington - Correspondence, 1944 - 1945 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Cipriano, Ralph - Special Representative Designation and Mayflower Hotel Reservation, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Cipriano, Ralph - Letters of Recommendation to U.S. President and Attorney General, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Testimonial Luncheon for Earl D. Krewson, 03/05/1949 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Cipriano, Ralph - Correspondence and Membership Cards, 1950 - 1958 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Italian-American Events in Washington, DC, 1950 - 1959 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- "The Evening Star," Washington, DC - "Columbus Honors Columbus" photograph, 10/12/1951 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Lido Civic Club of Washington, 1952 - 1959 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Italian-American Events in Washington, DC, 1960 - 1968 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Lido Civic Club of Washington, 1960 - 1968 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Cipriano, Ralph - U.S. Treasury Department Award, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Cipriano, Ralph - Correspondence and Photographs, 1961 - 1968 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Cipriano, Ralph - Correspondence and Reverend Edward B. Bunn Obituary, 1970 - 1975 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Lido Civic Club of Washington, 1970 - 1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Cipriano Family - Correspondence and Ralph Cipriano Obituaries, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Lido Civic Club, Ralph Cipriano, and Italian American Events, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)